Sved Muhammad Bilal Fahim

syed.m.bilalfahim@gmail.com |+92 3172665879 | Karachi, Pakistan <u>LinkedIn |GitHub</u>

SUMMARY

As a final-year computer science student, I am passionate about data science and product management. Over the past three years, I have applied my programming skills in languages such as R, Python, and SQL, as well as data visualization tools like PowerBI and Tableau, to complete various freelance projects on Fiverr. Recently, I have developed a strong interest in pursuing a career in product management, and I am currently seeking full-time opportunities to explore this field further.

EDUCATION

Degree	Institute	Graduation Year	CGPA/ %
BS in Computer Science (BSCS)	Institute of Business Administration, Karachi (IBA)	May 2023	3.17
Higher Secondary School Certificate (HSSC)	Commecs College, Karachi	2018	76.3%
Secondary School Certificate (SSC)	White House Grammar School, Karachi	2016	87%

WORK EXPERIENCE

Daraz - Alibaba Group

Nov 2022 - Feb 2023

Product & Program Design Intern - Regional (DAS)

Daraz Advertising Solution (DAS) is a platform that offers advertising and marketing solutions to brands and sellers on the marketplace. With DAS, they can promote their products or brand page without relying on a third-party agency."

- Gained proficiency in the private traffic tool, created end-to-end guide/ training deck, and trained regional business stakeholders from Nepal, Bangladesh, Myanmar, and Pakistan with 100% clarity.
- Managed issue resolution of private traffic tool led bi-weekly stakeholder meetings to discuss bugs/feedback, and successfully reduced/managed over 80% of issues in less time than expected.
- Assisted in executing end-to-end UATs on existing product with 45+ use cases to validate data and attribution metrics and collaborated in documenting detailed findings in comprehensive PRD.
- Centralized new and existing product details in PMO which resulted in a successful private traffic tool relaunch with enhanced 100% clarity.
- Consolidated the KPIs of the internal and external dashboards and came up with the data requirement document (DRD).
- Proposed a path forward for the legacy tool and drafted a BRD 2.0 which proposes product enhancements as well as a mass launch of Private Traffic (to all Sellers instead of selecting accounts) as the top funnel feature of the DAS umbrella.

Fiverr Oct 2020 – Present

Programming, Data Mining/Modelling and Automation Freelancer

- Successfully completed 60+ data analytics projects using R and Python, covering regression, classification, clustering, exploratory data analysis on complex datasets, and presenting insights in a detailed report.

YallaMotor June 2022 – Aug 2022

Tech Intern

"YallaMotor.com is an automobile portal for the Middle East where you can find the latest new cars, used cars, car prices, car reviews and auto businesses."

- Acquired knowledge of Ruby on Rails that helped gain a deeper understanding of the website structure of the company.
- Led the development of a bug-tracking web application using Ruby on Rails, allowing developers and project managers to prioritize and track software's progress and errors effectively.

Viheal Pakistan March 2022 – Aug 2022

Data Analyst Intern

"Viheal is a Pakistani Health startup which is determined to offer best health services to people in improving their health outcomes and transforming their lives."

- Collected and processed patient data for an elderly care service in 2022 to aid in decision-making and improvements.
- Developed a dashboard showcasing daily vitals trends of patients and their relationship with factors such as food, exercise, and sleep.

Afiniti June 2020 – July 2020

Quality Assurance Intern

- Performed user acceptance testing (UAT) to check the stability and integrity of a system which will be used by customer service agents.
- Identified the issues/bugs within the system and reported them to developers.

PROJECTS & REPORT

- **Final Year Project:** Developing a web-based Human Resource Management System as a final year project along with team to enable companies to hire new talent and allow users to apply for different job positions across various companies through a single platform. Responsible for product design using Figma and front-end development of the webpage.
- Used Python and R-Language to analyze and predict airline on-time performance data with an accuracy of 96% including arrival and departure delays.
- Used machine learning to analyze and predict heart failure in patients using 13 clinical features. Achieved an accuracy of over 80% using various algorithms.
- Applied Neural Network techniques to analyze MNIST data for handwriting recognition and achieved over 80% accuracy in predictions.

ACHIEVEMENTS & CERTIFICATIONS

- Recipient of 100% Ehsaas Trust Scholarship for the 4-year degree program at the Institute of Business Administration (IBA) Karachi.
- Ranked among the top 10 candidates in the Institute of Business Administration (IBA) aptitude test results.
- Completed Data Science R: Basics Course from HarvardX (EDX).
- Gained Proficient SQL Certification from **Triple Byte**.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR

- Participated in a Peace Promoting Conference "Camp Himalayas" by Youth Impact.
- Executive Council Member for IBA Entrepreneurship Club for the year 2021.
- Assistant Director Creatives for IBA Branding and Advertising Conference (IBAC 6.0) 2020

SKILLS